APRIL COPES

Fullstack Developer

OVERVIEW

Hi. My name is April. Prior to pursuing a career in software development, I was an industrial electrician specializing in PLC automation and conveyor installations. Since then, I have gained vast experience with full-stack JavaScript development, frameworks and technologies. I am open to opportunities where I can contribute my knowledge and understanding into an organization in need of skilled, dedicated and goal oriented individuals.

CONTACT

Cell: 862 279 1359 Address: Newark, NJ

Portfolio: www.aprilcopes.com Email: antdevelopment1@gmail.com Github: github.com/antdevelopment1 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/april-copes/

SKILLS

JavaScript SOL Git / Github Node.js HTML5 **AJAX** CSS3 **RESTful API** React **Express JSON** Vue.js **PostgreSQL** Webflow MySQL Arduino MongoDB I/O Circuitry

VOULENTEER EXPERIENCE

Digital Crafts (2019 - Present)

 Held weekly lectures on data structures, algorithms, Big O Notation, and interview preparation for immersive students

Locksley Logic (2019 - Present)

 Provides free software development tutoring, and mentorship to citizens in local communities

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CONSULTANT & FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

WILKERSON STAFFING LLC (MAR 2018 - PRESENT)

• Collaborates with CEO and VP to build custom applications catered to the conveyor installations industry.

DEVELOPER IN RESIDENCE FULLSTACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

DIGITALCRAFTS FULLSTACK IMMERSIVE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM (FEB 2018 - APR 2018)

• Supports lead instructor to help convey programming fundamentals to students. Assists with pair programming an debugging full stack applications.

INDUSTRIAL ELECTRICAL SUPERVISOR

WILKERSON CONVEYOR INSTALLATIONS (JUL 2016 - OCT 2018)

- Learned to orchestrate and effectively lead a team of industrial electricians to implement critical changes to existing electrical conveyor systems
- Advanced understanding of electrical schematics, PLC's, and I/O circuitry
- Oversaw the completion of critical system upgrades for projects with budgets ranging from \$10,000 to \$150,000+ throughout the country

MUSIC INSTRUCTOR

ROK TEC MUSIC (JUN 2009 - DEC 2014)

• Lead Instructor at Rock Tech Music. Teaching guitar and bass to children and adults from beginner to advanced skill levels.

EDUCATION

DIGITAL CRAFTS | STUDENT

16 WEEK FULLSTACK IMMERSIVE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM (SEP 2018 - JAN 2019)

Experience developing full stack JavaScript applications using MEAN / MERN stack Experience debugging advanced JavaScript apps and developing clean code using agile methodology

WILKERSON ELECTRICAL CONVEYOR INSTALLATIONS

INDUSTRIAL ELECTRICAL APPRENTICESHIP ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING JULY 2015 - AUG 2016

Studied how to interpret advanced electrical schematics and electrical engineering theory Gained experience making changes and upgrades to intricate electrical systems while complying with code and industry standards